In the time between winter and summer,
the number of residents increased again.
After discussing it with everyone, we decided
to call this place The Great Tree Village.
And I ended becoming
the mayor of this village.
Even though I'm the mayor now,
my day-to-day routine
hasn't really changed at all.
Mayor!
A messenger from the Demonic Kingdom has arrived!
A messenger from the Demonic Kingdom?
Farming Life in Another World
When you open your eyes and see
that pure white light, the story begins
Stepping forth into a new world,
what kind of flowers will we make bloom?
Even if it's cloudy,
even if we get dirty from a puddle
We continue on
There's a future we can't imagine
waiting for us, I'm sure of it
Meeting, meeting, and connecting
If you smile,
everyone around you will smile too
Let's plant a small seed and nurture it
One day it'll become a large flower
Turn regrets and failures into fuel
So that you're overflowing with colorful happiness
We'll join hands and share
Spread across the world, Flower Ring
My name is Beezel.
I'd like to have an audience with
the person in charge here.
It's my first job as the mayor.
That's me.
You?
I'm the mayor, Hiraku.
Very well.
In commemoration of
our becoming acquainted...
Please accept this gift.
Thank you for your kindness.
I have a message from the demon lord.
He would like to discuss
the status of this settlement here.
I don't think anyone owns
this particular plot of land or anything,
but I guess technically it's under
the control of the demon lord.
Does he want me to pay taxes...
Demon Lord
for all the time I've spent living on his land?
No wait, maybe he's going to tell me
to get off his property?
Maybe it would be wise for me
to ask Lu and Tia for their advice
before I do anything...
Alright, it's time for me to step up
and handle my duties as mayor.
If the demon lord is willing to
accept us living here on this land,
then I would be willing to offer part of
our harvest as payment of taxes.
First, I need to show that I have no intention
of rebelling against the demon lord!
As for the rate we pay...
I need to be strong for this part!
...how does 10% sound?
Was that too low?
Well then!
Are you satisfied with this arrangement?
Huh?
Y-yeah.
I'd like you guys to come pick it up
every year before winter starts.
I-I understand.
That's how we'll proceed from now on.
Huh? Is it settled already?
Hiraku Machio
The tax we pay will be 10%
of our total harvest.
However, this is limited to
what we grow in our fields.
We won't give them any of the milk, eggs,
honey or alcohol that we produce.
If the demon lord's people are
interested in anything else we produce,
then we'll enter trade negotiations.
I did end up feeling like I was
too aggressive with my negotiations...
I bid you all farewell.
...so I sent him home with a present.
I hope I handled that all the right way.
I think you did a pretty good job.
Since we're paying them taxes,
we're technically under
their protection from now on.
Indeed.
But still... 10%?
Usually the going rate is
supposed to be 50 or 60%.
Wha?
Having them come here to collect the
payment every year was a good decision.
It forces them to officially
recognize our residence here.
And if they're only coming
to collect once a year,
they won't be able to accurately
measure everything we produce.
In other words, we just bought
the protection of the demon lord
for a real tax rate of under 10%!
Well done, mayor.
R-really?
And to top it off, they brought this present.
Almighty
The almighty medicine that works if you
drink it or apply it directly to an injury!
Wow.
What?!
They're submitting to our military force?
Yes.
Even though they have the strength
to defeat a wyvern...
One of the demon lord's four great generals
Grattz
Surely, they must have some ulterior motive?
One of the demon lord's four great generals
Randan
Beezel
I had the same suspicion,
but I had no choice but to accept their conditions.
But why?!
The vampire princess and
the angel of annihilation were there.
What?!
The great sage Lulucy and
the strongest of all the angels?!
No way...
And that's not all.
There was an army of high elves
and a pack of inferno wolves.
That's absurd!
And the group that guided me to the leader
was the trio of killer angels.
I thought my life was over.
If that's the case, then I can see how they
were able to take down a wyvern.
After all that, he suggested that they be
under the protection of the demon lord's army.
I couldn't refuse.
If I had, they would have immediately
become an enemy force.
The silver lining in all of this is that
we were able to negotiate amicably.
No way... this can't be happening...
They even gave me a gift.
What is it?
I haven't looked yet.
Open it.
We need to consult the demon lord first.
It's over... we're finished...
And what if it's something dangerous?
Hey, wait!
Fruit?
They look kind of like appos,
but the shape and color are much nicer.
Better check if they're poisoned.
Hey!
Wow, this is really good! It's great!
You can't just eat those!
This cloth... it can't be.
Is this from a demon spider?
No, a great demon spider?
What?!
Didn't one of those fight one of
the previous demon lords to a standstill?
They have one of those, too?!
I'm resigning!
Randan?
Randan!
My name is Dryme.
I am the one true ruler of the dragons.
This is a present from us.
Please accept it.
Okay...
Wow!
It looks really expensive,
but this seems like kind of a violent gift.
Th-thank you for the wonderful gift.
It's our pleasure.
So, what's the purpose of
your visit here today?
Of course. My master, Lord Dryme,
has his lair located to the south of here.
There's quite a bit of distance between us,
but we still consider you our neighbors.
We've come here to offer a formal greeting.
That's very polite of you.
By the way, is there a reason
your master is bowing his head?
My apologies for that.
Master, please raise your head.
Huh? Okay.
Since you came all the way here,
I want to invite you inside,
but that seems kind of hard
given your size.
You're absolutely right.
Master, please change into
your smaller form.
Now then, please introduce yourself again.
My name is Dryme.
I am the one true ruler of the dragons.
Did he memorize that line
so he wouldn't mess up his introduction?
Man, this place is great!
This booze is great!
Ah, I'm not going home!
I'm living here!
You can't do that.
There will be a lot of people who will
get upset if you don't protect your home.
I'll be fine here.
I can intercept any attackers!
I'm sure you could,
however it would be a nuisance for
everyone here if you were to stay too long.
Now then, let's leave while they're still
happy to call us their guests.
They were even kind enough
to give us some gifts.
Yeah, they gave us those
appo looking things.
They're called apples.
And don't worry,
they gave us plenty of them.
Alright, I get it.
I'm heading home!
Don't transform until you're outside!
I know I should have thought of this sooner...
but I should really decide how
The Great Tree Village
is going to handle visitors,
welcome guests or otherwise.
Diplomatic relations, huh?
This is all getting
really complicated really fast.
I've been thinking about
a lot of things since then,
and I've decided that it's not good
for us to keep visitors outside
by the village entrance
when we're greeting them.
That said, I'm not comfortable
inviting them into our homes.
So I've decided that we should
build a guest house for visitors.
I was thinking that a house able to fit
four people would be enough.
What do you think?
No, I think that would be far too small.
She's right.
Anyone coming to this village needs to
climb mountains and make it through the forest.
Our visitors up until now have been servants
of the demon lord and dragons, however...
normally whenever people come here,
they'll be doing so in large groups.
Let's see.
I think we should play it safe
and build a house that can fit
about 30 people comfortably.
I see.
Okay then. We'll make the first floor
an open space designed to hold feasts.
And we can make the second floor
into bedrooms for our guests to stay in
if they want to stay here.
Sounds good.
And that's how we got started building
a guest house for any potential visitors.
Next, I wanted to work on how
we are greeting new guests.
Granmaria and the angels are
in charge of defending the perimeter,
and rather than finding visitors
and guiding them here,
they would capture visitors and
bring them to the village entrance.
On top of that, whenever Zabuton
would sound the warning alarm...
Let's go.
Let's get them.
Let's do it.
...everyone would grab their weapons
and get ready for battle.
Let's do this!
...everyone would grab their weapons
and get ready for battle.
It's a long way off from a proper welcome.
So we came up with a new signal for visitors.
Lea and the elves made a bell.
Next, we discussed
how we treated our guests.
I suggested that Lu, Tia, and I
would great our guests.
Welcome
I cannot agree with using
such a small welcoming party.
She's right.
Enemies might try to sneak in
disguised as visitors.
My idea was rejected.
So we added a few high elves, ogre maids,
and lizardmen to our welcoming party.
Flora wanted to be part of
our welcoming party as well,
but I asked her to keep an eye on any visitors
that stayed here until nightfall.
Understood. Please leave it to me.
If you'd like, I can keep watch
the entire time they're here.
It was then I learned
that Flora and Lu could go several days
without sleeping and be fine.
But I still told them not to overdo it.
All the preparation we did got put to use...
much sooner than I expected.
I'm Garf.
We're from a place in the mountains
east of here called Howling Village.
We want to establish relations
with your village.
I'll handle this.
That must have been a tough journey.
The Great Tree Village welcomes you.
Thank you.
I'd like to take you to our guest house
so that you can rest.
Is this your whole group?
Yeah, it is.
I see.
Then we'll treat the others as enemies.
What's she talking about.
Sorry about that.
It looks like we had a few stragglers.
Well that was dangerous.
You should really make sure everyone
is together before you enter the village.
And it would be wise to behave
yourselves while you're here.
There are people that even I need to
watch myself around here.
I understand.
You have my word.
Then follow me.
Welcome.
Great. We've finally taken our first step
towards real hospitality.
Stay here for a while.
What are you doing?
It seems more like you're trapping enemies
than welcoming guests.
Mayor. Haven't you noticed?
Whenever visitors come to
establish relations with our village,
they always bring some sort of
offering with them.
Even that dragon brought something.
You think they aren't friendly?
I can't say for sure yet.
If they don't follow the normal rules,
then they don't get the normal
visitor treatment. That's all.
I see.
Them leaving two troops
hiding in the woods concerns me.
That's why we knocked our
hospitality level down a notch for them.
Didn't Kudel or the other girls
spot those troops?
They noticed them but decided those troops
weren't a threat and ignored them.
I'll punish them later.
Go easy on them.
Okay. I'll let them off with a warning.
Is something the matter?
Oh, it's nothing.
It's just that the food you made for Dryme-
You think this food isn't up to that standard?
Well, something like that...
I'm sure that you've already
realized by now,
but this is the difference in treatment
between guests who brought that sword,
and those who brought nothing.
I guess so.
Oh, um... do you not plan on
offering them any wine?
I see.
I feel bad offering them such a meager meal.
Please rid yourself of such emotions.
She's right. They're supposed to be here
for important negotiations.
Our goal is to find out what they're after.
Everyone besides you was against
offering them any wine.
You forced us to do it.
And I'm glad that you all let me do it.
That said, it's just two cups per person.
Those were the restrictions put in place.
The fact remains that they
came all the way here.
Until we determine that they're really enemies,
I want to show them kindness.
First, I want to find out why they're here.
I'm sure I'm revealing my own
ignorance in asking this,
but what kind of place is Howling Village?
They say it's been around for 1,000 years,
but in reality, it's only about half that.
500 years, I think.
The older guys take pride in the weirdest stuff.
Ya got that right!
It's a village made up of five small
settlements of about 100 people or so,
and we call it Howling Village.
Most of the population are beastmen.
Ya got that right!
Howling Village is made up of people
who make their living hunting or mining.
Up until now, they've managed to survive
by trading with a human village
across the mountains,
but lately there's been some trouble there
and the trade between them
has become unstable.
That's why they're looking for
someone new to trade with.
And they settled on our Great Tree Village.
Where did you learn about our village?
We got word from one of
the demon lord's people.
Huh?
Man, if we stayed outside
hiding the whole time,
we would have missed this great meal.
I'm so glad we came out of hiding.
Why were you hiding in the first place?
You need to be on guard
the first time you visit a new place.
Plus if something happens there,
someone needs to go back
and tell the rest of the village.
I see...
She's doing a good job of
gathering information.
I can count on her.
It turned out that the beastmen from
Howling Village weren't trying to trick us,
and really did want to
establish trade relations.
Now then, onto our trade agreement.
Yeah.
We're not really interested in
normal economic trade.
We'd like to simply trade
physical goods in an open market.
We don't use any currency
in our village, after all.
It's the same here.
Currency, huh?
I'm sure we'll need to create it someday.
Normally I'd want to open up
a market in both of our villages,
but if it's possible we'd like you
to come to our village to trade.
The truth is that it was very difficult
for us to even get here this time.
Carrying goods all the way here
and back would be too much...
It's pretty much the same for us, though.
You live here.
Aren't you able to navigate
the forest easily?
Now that he mentions it...
Go forth!
maybe I can have Kuro and the dogs
carry the goods for us.
I understand.
So what do you want to trade
during our first visit?
We have goods made from
the ore we mine.
Paints, silverware, glassworks,
metalworks, and the like.
I want them! I want them all!
In exchange, we'd like to
receive foodstuffs.
Then we'll bring our food crops to trade!
Great!
And so began our trade relationship
with Howling Village.
About the whole present thing...
The truth is, until last night I didn't even
know people brought gifts when visiting.
Our village doesn't have a custom like that.
Don't worry about it.
I'll bring something next time!
That said, our village is poor,
so we won't be able to bring anything fancy.
That's okay.
What's important with gift giving
isn't the value of the gift,
but the thought behind it.
Hearing that makes me feel a lot better!
Before long, it was time to trade
with Howling Village.
I was planning on going, too...
You can't. It looks really bad if we
send our top man there right away.
Is that how things work?
Yes, it's how they work.
We drew lots and based on the results
I'll be acting on your behalf
for the duration of the trading.
Originally, it was going to take
ten days for them to travel there,
but Dryme agreed to take everyone there
in exchange for a barrel of wine.
After his first visit, Dryme decided to
start coming to hang out here regularly.
He always brings treasures
or weapons as gifts with him,
so no one complains about him.
Transporting everyone in exchange for
a barrel of wine was actually Dryme's idea,
so I took him up on the offer.
Okay then, we'll be off now.
Thanks for the wine, mayor.
Yeah!
Are they really going to show up?
Garf negotiated the
trade agreement with them.
They'll definitely show up!
We haven't even received word that
they've reached the mountain range yet...
Is that...
A-a dragon?!
Hey, it's coming this way!
Look at that!
A few days later
Good work.
How was it?
We were able to exchange everything
we took, and they loved it all.
They seemed to be hesitant at first
because they wouldn't go near
anything we brought.
But then I tried the "free samples" stuff
you told me about,
and before I knew it, a crowd had gathered.
They even sold the wine that was
supposed to be for me...
Did they now?
I guess you'll just have to drink
even more at dinner tonight.
You're the best, mayor!
You really know how to cheer me up.
In addition, the mayor of Howling Village
asked if some of their people
could come to live here.
We still need more people to work,
so I'd be happy to have them.
In total, there are 20 people
that want to come live here.
And they're all young women.
The fact of the matter is that right now
this village is in desperate need of more men.
If these keeps up any longer,
I'm afraid the village won't have a future.
Okay, but I have one condition.
If they can send at least two young men,
I'll happily accept everyone.
Understood.
Now the future of the village is secure.
My name is Sena.
We're all very grateful that
you've accepted us into your village.
We're mentally prepared for you
to use us however you see fit.
Just please don't abandon us.
Uh, I see that you've gone through a lot of
extreme mental preparation for you move here,
but anyways, we've got your beds ready.
Take your time and get acclimated there.
Take our time?
Yeah.
Once you're used to daily life here,
you can make requests for
what kind of house you want and stuff.
You don't need to worry about us
kicking you out or anything like that.
Thank you so much!
Sure.
By the way, are the men who
are moving here with you?
Of course!
We've brought three of them with us.
We brought you some young men like you asked!
Okay...
No, wait.
Can we?
Deliberation
Decision pending
Can we?
Just 5 years, or maybe 10 years from now!
No, that's...
Decision pending
It's definitely...
Just 5 years, or maybe 10 years from now!
Decision pending
I'm counting on you,
for the future of this village!
I can feel the soft seasonal winds,
gently on my fingertips
Let's search for what we love
in the clouds floating in the sky
Forget about the hands of the clock for now
Try taking one deep breath
The rainbow-colored scenery
will resonate with my heart
I'm sure any wish I have will come true
Because you're by my side
You make every day feel like a dream
At that warm and kind place
Keep showing me your smiling face forever
Next Time
Episode 8
The Researcher and the Two Princesses
Next Time